Fernando Samir Cruz Fama

Fortaleza CE Brasil

samirfama@gmail.com • 21 anos

www.linkedin.com/in/fernando-samir-data-scientist-and-analyst/ • https://samir-fama.github.io/

Summary of Qualifications

Data Scientist, developer of the Top 1 Best Open Source ChatBot with 7 billion parameters of 2023, silver medalist in the world's largest mathematics olympiad with a background in exact sciences from the most advanced class from my school, experience in scientific olympiad classes, and Mechatronic Engineering, Currently working on personal projects and providing freelance services as a Data Scientist. Driven by high performance to achieve aggressive goals, with strong analytical and problem-solving abilities, excellent communication skills, and a high level of emotional intelligence. Extensive experience in programming artificial intelligences and working with large databases, producing reports, and delivering substantial results. Committed to working on data analysis and artificial intelligence development.

Academic Education

- BS Mechatronics Engineering Federal Institute of Education, Science and Technology of Ceará Sep/2020 on a break
- High School, Especial Class ITA / IME Farias Brito Central Completed in 2019

Professional Experience

12/2020 to date - self-employed (Personal Projects + Freelance)

Position: Data Scientist

- I developed various advanced Als in sectors such as health, computer vision, deep fakes, financial analysis, and many others. Alongside, I created chatbots with significant expertise.
- I highlight SamirGPT-v1, the Top 1 Open Source LLM of 2023 among those with 7 billion parameters, exclusively developed by me. Acclaimed as one of the best globally today, it serves as evidence of my profound understanding of LLMs.

08/2021 to date - self-employed (Algorithmic Trading Operations Using Artificial Intelligence)

Position: Data Scientist

- I have developed hundreds of highly profitable machine learning and statistical models through model training and insights extraction from database analyses.
- I have created hundreds of financial reports for data analysis, providing valuable insights to optimize profits and select the most effective models

12/2022 until 10/2023 - self-employed (Video Generation for Social Media Using Artificial Intelligence)

Position: Data Scientist

- I achieved nearly 100 million views thanks to the machine learning models I developed for content creation on social media in the project. I even managed to grow an account from 0 to 5 million monthly views in less than 2 months.
- I performed the Extraction, Transformation, and Loading (ETL) process for hundreds of thousands of videos using Python. I was responsible for managing a database with over 100 GB of data and led the entire data modeling process.

<u>Languages</u>

• English – Advanced | Portuguese – Native.

Softwares / Courses / Certifications

Tensorflow | PyTorch | Keras | scikit-learn | huggingface | transformers | accelerator | AutoTrain Advanced | OpenAl Gym | OpenCV | Pillow | pandas | numpy | statsmodels | seaborn | Matplotlib | plotly | moviepy | Ffmpeg | Excel | Power Bl | Tableau | Python | SQL | C++ | MQL5 | Selenium | bs4 | scrapy | requests freeCodeCamp - Certification in Data Analysis - Data Analysis with Python IA Expert Academy - Al and ML Certification - Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning: The Complete Guide

- LinkedIn Learn Tableau Certification Tableau Essential Training
- LinkedIn Learn Excel Certification Excel Essential Training
- Kaggle SQL Certification Intro to SQL & Advanced SQL